- Previously on "Gotham"...
- Welcome home, Bruce.
The Court's readying a weapon
that could destroy the city.
You've done it.
You've weaponized the virus.
We have to escape.
There's only one way
that's gonna happen.
- We work together.
- So that we may be free
to murder each other outside.
How do you expect to win, Oswald?
I have an army of Hugo Strange's
monsters at my command.
Selina!
- Selina, stop!
- He's not Bruce!
Where is Bruce?
Bruce is serving a greater purpose.
We found another owl.
We think this map indicates
the secret hideouts of the Court.
James Gordon.
You loved him, and
that love doomed Mario.
- But guess who's really to blame?
- I am.
We will destroy the Court of Owls
and then you will do whatever I say.
- Won't you?
- Yes.
The virus sample
we got from Hugo Strange,
- it's gone.
- Maybe Lucius took it.
No, Lee has it, too.
The day of judgment has come to Gotham.
And to the Court of Owls.
Three years ago,
a great crime was committed.
Thomas and Martha Wayne were murdered.
Their blood is on the Court's hands.
On your hands.
Thomas Wayne stood against the Court.
He threatened to expose us.
He paid the price.
And my mother?
She had to die as well?
Why is Bruce Wayne here?
He has come to pass judgment.
Enough of this.
You are the leader of the Court.
No one disputes that.
But you absent yourself from
Gotham for years at a time.
Decisions had to be made.
The ruling council
stands by its actions.
They were your parents, Bruce.
You knelt in their blood
that night in the alley.
Let blood avenge blood.
Give the order.
You hesitated.
Next time, I won't.
I promise.
Mm. Mm.
No,
I know you won't.
Mm.
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
- Keep me informed.
- Bullock, any word from Bruce?
Alvarez said he wasn't at that location,
but they're checking out
the next black site on the map.
All right, everybody knows the score.
The Court of Owls is planning
an attack on the city.
They've kidnapped Bruce Wayne.
And now they know we're coming for them.
So be ready for anything. Let's go.
This is the ruling council.
Who could've done this?
Straight up execution.
Gordon.
We got a breather.
Gordon... traitor.
Yeah.
I'm a traitor. Where's Bruce Wayne?
Where's the bomb?
We were betrayed.
The leader, Bruce Wayne,
they killed us.
That geezer's lying.
If Master Bruce was in that room,
he's being held prisoner or something
I mean, it's absurd to think
he had anything to do with that carnage.
I still don't get
why the leader would whack
his own ruling council.
I mean, does this mean the virus
bomb plan thing's off?
Until we have the bomb
in our possession,
we have to assume the plan's still on.
Maybe the leader was cleaning house.
So what's the next step?
Because we hit every spot
on that crystal owl and all we got
were dead people wearing owl masks.
We run their identities,
we track their holdings,
we see where it leads us.
It worked with Kathryn.
Yeah? And how long's that
gonna take then, mate?
We're all trying to find Bruce, Alfred.
We're doing everything we can.
Well...
if only that were enough, eh?
He's worried about the kid.
I don't blame him.
I have no idea how Bruce fits
into the Court's plans.
But what we saw today,
them executing their own,
they're zealots, capable of anything.
Gordon, those unis you put on
Thompkins' brownstone,
they called, she's home.
I know what you're thinking, brother,
Lee stealing the virus, that's weird.
But injecting herself? Hmm?
This is Lee we're talking about.
You didn't hear what she
said to me last night, Harvey.
Okay, fine.
Go.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Come again?
I said, Oswald Cobblepot is alive.
He's lying.
I wish that were true.
He disappeared for days,
and then he shows up
with some insane story
about him and Penguin
being trapped in bird cages
and escaping together?
- What'd you say you used, pudding?
- Red Jell-O.
How stupid do you think we are?
You really want me to answer that?
It's a setup.
Well, you would know,
being an expert in betrayal.
- Keep pushing me.
- Calm down.
Both of you. In the
interest of cooperation...
...your partner's backstabbing
actually led to an answer
you were seeking.
Who... controls... Gotham?
It's an organization calling
themselves the Court of Owls.
And?
Who are they? What do they want?
Well, unfortunately,
my interaction was limited
to a woman named Kathryn,
who had a stern updo.
But I can tell you there's
no interest in the underworld.
So, at least for now,
you shouldn't worry about them.
You should...
...worry about Penguin.
I'm sorry, how is that
our problem again?
You're the one that shot him
and dumped in the river.
Oh, Butch.
I knew that your hand was made of lead,
- forgot that your brain was as well.
- Cute.
Thank you.
The three of you conspired
to help me murder him.
So in Penguin's eyes,
we're all guilty.
He's right.
I'll get a team to hit
Penguin's house right away.
Don't bother.
He knows it's the first place we'd stop.
He's probably stowed away
in some safe house.
Good thing I know where they all are.
Here we go. Together again.
Oh, I should've told you,
Penguin's recruited an army
of Hugo Strange's monsters.
Yeah, we'll see.
I'll take it from here.
Head back to the station.
Lee?
It's Jim.
Hello, Jim.
I knew you'd come.
Are you surprised?
You look surprised.
There's been a squad car
outside my house all morning.
That tells me you knew
I stole the virus.
Thought you'd assume I'd inject myself.
I'd hoped I was wrong.
Well, that'll teach you.
Can I get you something? I know
how you like your whiskey.
Why'd you do this?
You know why, Jim.
You blame yourself over
what happened to Mario?
You didn't shoot him,
you didn't infect him.
Wasn't your fault.
I'd have to disagree
with you on that one.
But, honestly, the whole
argument is moot at this point.
No, it isn't, Barnes was infected
for weeks before the
virus fully took hold.
We can get you help.
I'm no virologist, but I'd say
we missed the boat on that one.
Come on, we can fight this.
Come with me.
Don't you want to know what the virus
has brought out in me, Jim?
What it's shown me?
No.
My love for you.
It's pretty obvious
when you think about it.
Perfect Dr. Lee Thompkins.
Why would she be drawn to a
man with so much darkness?
Such an appetite for violence?
Unless something inside her... liked it.
Craved it.
Needed it.
That's not true.
The virus has shown me how
to give in to my deepest desires.
And I will no longer deny myself
what I really want.
There's a problem, though,
Jim, isn't there?
You know what the problem is, don't you?
Yeah, you need help.
No, the problem...
is that you are always denying yourself
who you really are.
But I can help you with that.
You see, Jim, I have a secret.
Harvey, I found something.
Right. This is a mock-up
of the map that Lucius made
of all the Court's black sites, right?
One problem.
The place where Bruce and I found
the original crystal owl
should be here.
Marked.
But it's not.
Well, maybe it's an old owl
that hasn't been updated.
No, mate, no. You're missing
the point. No, look.
The Court hasn't marked all hideouts.
So how did you find the house
when you stole the owl?
Well, it was this little, uh,
Ukrainian smuggling firm
called the Whisper Gang.
And you're thinking that maybe
they know of other locations?
Do you know where
we can find these clowns?
I do.
If there's any left alive.
What's he so angry about?
Oh, we hunted down these freaks
- to help him destroy Nygma and Barbara.
- Mm-hmm.
We got this Freeze guy
and your pal Bridgit,
who does the... the fire thing.
Wait, you found Bridgit?
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
Pengy disappeared the other day,
and she and Freeze figured
he wasn't coming back,
so they split.
- Can you find her?
- Why?
There is a war coming
between me, Ed Nygma,
and Barbara Kean.
I need my army.
What's in it for me?
My gratitude.
Hmm.
Fine.
Uh, you guys,
we got company... not the good kind.
Ivy, let's go.
Well, I can't leave Penguin.
Oh, suit yourself.
You do have a way out, right?
Of course. This is a safe house.
Oswald!
Edward.
No army of monsters, huh? Such a shame.
- You want to kill him, or can I?
- Wait.
Something's wrong.
Oh, Ed.
So smart.
No!
Damn it!
Bravo, Oswald!
But you're just delaying the inevitable.
Where's your far better half?
Where you going, kitty cat?
Bruce.
What were you thinking about?
My parents.
I've wanted justice for them
for so long.
And now that I've achieved it...
What do you feel?
Failure.
I did not give the order.
You will get another chance
to prove yourself worthy.
Hello, Bruce.
It is good to see you again.
Hello, Professor.
Fascinating.
He's completely docile.
I'd like to hear your techniques,
sensei.
One day, Professor.
Show me the weapon.
I told you, Bruce,
that I did not serve the Court.
I... we made use of the Court
for our own ends.
The one I serve believes
you have a great destiny.
My task has been to prepare you for it,
but a final step remains
in your journey.
This detonator will trigger the bomb.
Thousands will be
infected with the virus,
the city will be torn apart,
and out of the ashes...
a dark hero will rise.
You.
Mm.
When the time comes, you
must press this button.
Are you ready to embrace
your destiny, Bruce?
Yes.
Gotham must fall.
Jim, me and Alfred got
a possible location on Bruce
from a bunch of Ukrainian
yucks wearing muzzles,
if you can believe it.
Give me a call when you can.
- Where the hell is Gordon, anyway?
- He had to do something.
We're gonna have to give you a badge
or something one of these days.
Please be very careful with this.
GCPD! Nobody...
Go get Bruce!
Don't move a muscle.
Obviously, I surrender.
You know where to take it.
Bruce!
Oh, thank God.
So you're the top boy, are you?
The leader?
Step away from Bruce, or I swear to God
I will shoot you straight in the face.
You had best put down
the weapon, Mr. Pennyworth.
Not bloody likely, mate.
Bruce?
Bruce, get out of the light.
No, Alfred.
I will not let you hurt him.
What's he done to you?
He has lifted the burden of my past.
Revealed my true destiny.
Gotham must fall by my hand.
No.
Bruce!
- Dwayne.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, Steve, put this animal in a cage.
I'll be back
to bust your head in a minute.
Alfred, hey.
Are you okay?
Far from it.
I mean, the leader of the Court
has turned Bruce into
some kind of, like,
weird zombie zealot.
I mean, I wouldn't have believed it
if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes.
I think he wants Bruce
to detonate the bomb.
- What?!
- Bruce said something about
it being his destiny.
How Gotham must fall by his hand.
This is bad.
We got to find that friggin' bomb.
Let's go see baldy-locks
and see what he can tell us.
Harvey.
Heard from the unis at Doc Thompkins'.
No sign of her or Gordon or his car.
Put a BOLO out on Jim Gordon.
- And put one out on Lee Thompkins, too.
- I'm right here, Harvey.
Lee. Hey.
It's good to see you.
You wouldn't happen to know
where Jim is, would you?
As a matter of fact,
he's probably waking up
right about now.
Lee.
Lee...!
Lee...
Lee! Lee...!
Lee!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy, everybody.
Guns down, people. It's all right.
Everybody just step back.
You really did it, huh?
You injected yourself with the virus?
You're just like Jim, you seem
to think it's a bad thing.
Where is he?
He went to see you at your brownstone,
and now we can't get in touch with him.
Well, look at you,
all worried about your hero.
You put him up on this pedestal,
forced him to deny his true self.
I am going to free Jim
and show everyone who he really is.
Where the hell is he?
He's in a coffin, six feet underground.
Did you kill him?
Who said anything about killing him?
Oh, bloody hell.
I said he was in a coffin.
He's not dead.
Not yet.
Oh, geez.
I forgot how jumpy
everybody is around here.
Jim, are you there?
Jim, you there?
Lee, what the hell are you doing?
Stay calm.
You've got to conserve your air.
Listen to me...
Little late for that.
Why don't you say hi
to Harvey and the gang?
Harvey? You there?
We're here, buddy. Where are you?
Harvey, she's got the virus.
- She's buried me alive...
- Shh.
I do the talking.
Now, if you're quiet,
I'll let you listen.
So, here's the deal.
I buried Jim Gordon alive
in a location that you might
find if you looked long enough,
but certainly not
before he runs out of air.
Meaning, I'm the only one
who knows where he is.
But...
now here's the kicker...
I left him a way out.
You hear that, Jim?
I left you an escape hatch.
Have you found it yet?
You should've found it by now.
You left me the virus.
I told you I would help you
find your darkness.
Now,
I can't do it for you.
You've got to do it yourself.
I won't. I won't do it, Lee.
You've got two options.
You can take the virus,
and find the strength
and get out of there,
or you can make that coffin
your permanent home.
Lee, please. Please.
In the name of all
that is holy and not insane...
...tell us where he is.
I swear to God, I'll let you
walk right out of here.
Tell us where you buried him.
Why would I want to walk
out of here, Harvey?
I'm gonna miss the look
on all of your faces
when he takes that virus.
And seeing that he's got roughly
an hour left of oxygen,
I'm not gonna have long to wait.
Can I get a cup of coffee?
Get the lady a cup of coffee.
Put her in a cell.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna bite.
All right, everyone,
Bruce Wayne is still missing.
There's still a freaking
terrorist attack
that could go down at any minute,
so get back to your jobs,
do what you're supposed to be doing.
Let me worry about Jim Gordon.
Jim.
It's me. You there, buddy?
Harvey.
These radios run
on a shortwave frequency.
I've got to be close.
Get it over to Lucius.
He should be able to run down
a general fix.
Hang tight, we're on it.
Let's go.
All right.
Conserve your breath.
Stay calm.
I'm not working for Penguin.
So you were just holed up
together for kicks?
No.
- Ivy just asked me to come by.
- Why?
None of your business, lunk.
Now I got to take lip off a kid?
You're friends with
that firebug, aren't you?
Her name's Bridgit.
Penguin's army of monsters deserted him.
And he needed your help finding them.
You're gonna tell Penguin
that you know where this Bridgit is
and that you'd like to meet.
And we'll take care of the rest.
Fine.
But I need cash to get out of town.
- Fine.
- And nothing happens to Ivy.
She's stupid, but not a traitor.
Those things aren't mutually exclusive.
Shoo. The grown-ups need to talk.
Oh, and forgive me if I don't
want you knowing the details.
That didn't work out so well last time.
Bye, now.
How much longer
are we gonna put up with this?
Jim.
Harvey, what'd you find?
You were right about the walkie.
It's got a one mile radius.
Lucius couldn't trace a signal,
but when we looked at a map,
we figured there was only
one place she could take you:
Jackson Park.
I should've known.
But that's nothing but dense forest.
- You'll never...
- It's a place to start.
We're gonna find you, brother,
I promise.
Harvey. Listen, I know he's your mate,
but with everything else
that's going on,
with Bruce missing, the bomb,
you certain searching for Jim
is the best use of your time?
If the situation were reversed,
he'd do the same for me.
Besides, I got you.
- What do you mean?
- I want you to squeeze Strange,
find out everything he knows.
I saw how you dealt
with that Kathryn bird.
- You like to get your hands dirty.
- Wait, are you sure about this, mate?
I want you to get your hands
really dirty.
I want you to find out where
the leader's taking Bruce.
Find the bomb,
and however much or little
is left of Strange after that,
even if it's just a pinky,
we will throw in jail.
Thanks.
Campos.
Call the K-9 unit, have them meet us
in Jackson Park, now!
You can't save him, Harvey.
He's gonna take the virus.
And we're gonna be together
the way we were meant to be!
It's gonna be beautiful.
Get off.
I find this shouting
and screaming deeply upsetting.
It affects my concentration.
And my grip!
Please. Don't let me fall.
We can discuss this
in a civilized manner!
Oh, that's rich, coming
from the likes of you.
Who's about to poison
thousands of people
and turn them into raving lunatics!
Now, where is Bruce Wayne?
And where is the bomb?
If I tell you, you drop me.
I end up dead, either way.
Self-preservation, is it?
That's your game?
All right, then, Humpty.
I got a swapsie for you.
Down you pop.
Your freedom for Bruce Wayne.
You don't have
the authority to let me go.
I didn't have the authority
just to hang you
off the side of a bloody building, did I?!
Hey, see that fire escape over there?
That leads directly to the street
and to your freedom.
Now, I won't stop you.
I just want to know where my boy is.
All right.
The leader has taken Bruce
to Wayne Enterprises.
They'll have a view of the street below
as it fills with people
affected by the virus,
- but you're too late.
- Why?
What time is the bomb going off?
5:00 p.m., but that's not what I mean.
The Bruce Wayne you know is gone.
His mind is no longer his own.
Oh, you're so wrong.
You have got no idea
how strong that boy is.
Now, I'm a man of my word.
You can walk.
Just as soon as you wake up.
I don't know what you mean...
Slag.
You seem troubled.
I hope it was not the encounter
with your manservant.
No.
If this is my destiny,
I do not want to fail.
You won't, Bruce.
All this,
everything the Court of Owls
set in motion,
everything I have done, has been
to prepare you for this moment,
and afterward,
I will bring you to the one
whose vision has singled you out.
He is very eager to meet you.
Harvey.
- Anything?
- Nothing yet.
Covered about 30 acres.
How you holding up?
It's getting hard to breathe.
Stay off the walkie;
you got to conserve your air.
That shouldn't be hard.
- I'm running low on battery.
- Well, quit your yapping.
Harvey, there's too much
ground to cover.
You've done everything you could.
Okay.
Go to plan B.
Take the virus.
No.
If you don't, you'll die.
Take the virus,
and we'll figure something out.
I'm not gonna take the virus.
I won't become a monster.
Hold on.
Alfred.
Strange said the bomb is due
to detonate at 5:00 p.m.
5:00?! That's in, like,
20 minutes! Where?
He never said where, but he did say
that the leader and Bruce are heading
directly to Wayne Enterprises
to watch the fallout.
Now, the rooftop looks
directly onto Union Station.
The bomb's due to go off, slap, bang,
in the middle of rush hour.
Wait, w-whoa, whoa! Stop!
I want every available
uni to Union Station!
I want it evacuated now! Go!
- K-9s stay with me.
- Harvey, at 5:00 p.m.,
Union Station is gonna be packed.
Even with an evacuation,
thousands will be infected.
Not if we find the bomb first.
But I'm guessing it's not gonna
be sitting out in the open.
- No, it'll be hidden.
- Where?
Yesterday, Kathryn said,
"Gotham will fall when the clock stops."
What if she was talking
about a real clock?
Clock tower at Union Station.
Harvey?
Harvey, do you hear me?
Harvey, Harvey, you copy?
Jim, I lost you. Jim?
Jim!
In the old days,
loyalty meant something.
Don Falcone, Maroni,
even Fish.
They had their faults,
but they lived by codes.
Ed Nygma, Barbara Kean...
they wouldn't even be allowed
to sit at the same table as Don Falcone.
And yet, here I am,
forced to demean myself
to do battle with them.
Yeah, people are dumb.
Plants are better.
You can trust them.
I have no more safe houses.
No monsters.
I will not run from Ed Nygma!
Well, actually, you have one monster.
What?
Selina called. She found Bridgit.
She's gonna bring her by.
You're joking.
That's... wait.
Why is Selina suddenly helping me?
I don't know.
She was acting kind of weird.
Asking where we were, did we have guns.
I was like, "We're all alone, duh."
You idiot!
- It was a setup!
- No. No way.
Selina would never do that.
Well, unless they offered her money.
Hello again, Oswald.
Captain, over here.
I think I found something.
We got to get to Union Station.
That was Bullock.
Gordon's on his way to Union Station.
He's infected with the virus. Come on!
Hey...
You must be very proud of yourself, Ed,
thinking you outsmarted me.
Well, frankly, it wasn't
really a challenge.
Now, you're gonna do one
thing before you die.
Call me...
The Riddler.
No.
You have a choice, Oswald.
This can happen real quick
or it can take hours.
- Days. It will be...
- I'll take option "B," Ed.
Since saying
that ridiculous name
would be torture itself.
Very well.
Slow and painful it shall be.
Uh, hello? Do I get no say in all this?
- See how it feels?
- Guys, you hear something?
This is a trap?
No, not exactly.
Fish.
Hello, Oswald.
Now, see that there?
That's a look of respect.
Or is it fear?
Hi-ya, Fish.
- How you been?
- Well, let's see.
I was alive...
and then I was dead.
And then I was alive.
Things are looking up.
My, my, my.
Now, this is quite a gathering.
You have to love Gotham.
People always
pointing guns at each other.
Why are you here?
You...
shall...
see.
And as for you, whoever you may be,
please excuse us.
My little penguin and I...
will be leaving.
Please, carry on.
Woman always knew how
to make an entrance.
Attention, all passengers.
This is an emergency.
Please proceed to the nearest exit.
Gordon, there you are.
Attention, all passengers.
This is an emergency.
Please proceed to the nearest exit.
It's time.
Press the button.
Claim your destiny.
Let Gotham fall so you may rise.
No!
Whatever destiny he's sold you,
Bruce, he's lying.
- Press it, Bruce.
- Don't.
Bruce, don't.
I won't have him turn you
into a murderer.
This is an emergency.
Please proceed to the nearest exit.
Are you going to shoot me, Alfred?
I want to help you.
We'll reverse what he's done to you.
Bruce, if you press that detonator,
there's no coming back.
He won't shoot you.
He's weak, Bruce, but you are not.
Bruce, please.
Give me the detonator, son.
No. You will press it.
Hello, lover.
I guess we're gonna have company.
Seek out the Yuyan building.
Find the demon's head.
Fulfill your destiny.
Bruce.
When you're ready, come and find me.
It's only a matter of time.
It's too late.
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net